Igor E.

Singapore

Audit Manager-Financial Service/Asset Management

Summary

I have more than 6 years of experience in providing assurance services to a wide range of clients including asset management companies, real estate investment trusts, UCITS fund and Cayman Islands Monetary Authority (CIMA) registered funds (trust and company structure, master/feeder and stand-alone). I have extensive experience in the application of IFRS, SFS, Luxembourg GAAP, German GAAP US GAAP.

I am also involved in conducting regulatory compliance reviews for financial institutions, with a focus on reviewing asset management companies' compliance with the applicable local and overseas regulatory requirements.

I would describe myself as a very determined and highly motivated person. I do take my job seriously but I'm able to see things in perspective and believe I'm quite easy-going to work with. I'm an optimist rather than a pessimist – but I'm also a realist and I cope well when the going gets tough; I'm very good at finding solutions to problems. Above all, I would say I'm a positive and enthusiastic person – and I relish a challenge.

Experience

Audit Manager at PwC Singapore

July 2014 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Financial Service/Asset Management

Responsible for a portfolio of audit clients (Unit Trust, Hedge Funds, Private Equity, Fund Manager, Investment Company)

- -Conducting audit engagement under the relevant GAA/GAAS
- -Perform compliance review of licensed Fund Manager (RFMC, LFMC)
- -Budgeting and determination of resource requirements
- -Billing and iPower management
- -Organising engagement partner and quality review partner meetings for both planning and completion stages of the audit.
- Appraisals for staff members setting objectives at planning stage and completion of appraisals once audit is finalised

- Review of client audit files planning through to completion, incorporating review of financial statements in line with relevant GAAP and GAAS.
- Drafting board reports, engagement letters and audit representation letters.
- Developing client relationship with fund manager.
- Liaison in relation to planning of cross funds work with lead manager on relevant service provider.
- Manage requirements of staff/timing of job

Team Manager / Ambassador at PricewaterhouseCoopers - Service Delivery Center (PwC SDC) October 2014 - February 2015 (5 months)

Financial Services/Asset Management

Clients: Hedge Fund, Unit Trust

- Coached, train and develop auditing staff to upgrade their knowledge in Asset Management
- Managed a team of 8-10 people during the daily work
- Provided additional help and guidance to team members
- Achieved team and individual budgets and business plan/ performance objectives.
- Managed project financials, including budgets, WIPS, timely billing and collection and variance recognition.
- Maintained the highest technical and professional standard.
- Liased with overseas Engagement Teams

Senior Audit Associate at PwC Singapore

November 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Financial Services/Asset Management

Clients - Hedge Fund, Unit Trust, licensed Fund Manager, Investment Company

As a key member of our Core Audit Team,

- Examine financial and accounting records, other documents, and tangible items such as plant and equipment or watching certain processes or procedures being performed
- Test the organization's internal controls make judgments on significant estimates or assumptions that management made when they prepared the financial report
- Compliance review of licensed fund manager
- Appraisel of junior staff members

Senior Audit Associate at PwC Luxembourg

September 2009 - October 2012 (3 years 2 months)

Financial Services/Asset Management

As a key member of our Core Audit Team,

Clients - UCITS Funds (FCP, SICAV), Fund Manager under Lux GAAP

- examine financial and accounting records, other documents, and tangible items such as plant and equipment or watching certain processes or procedures being performed -
- -test some of the organization's internal controls make judgments on significant estimates or assumptions that management made when they prepared the financial report
- Appraisel of junior staff members

Consulting Intern at R&C International Lawyers

September 2007 - February 2008 (6 months)

- Support the Manager during the daily business
- Liase with German client in South Africa

Logistics at Bosch

September 2005 - February 2006 (6 months)

- Coordinate and adminstrate taks in respect the transport of products to the US subsidiaries/ clients

Education

ACCA

Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (ACCA), Accounting and Finance, 2011 - 2014 University of Applied Sciences Hof

Master's Degree, Accounting and Finance, 2004 - 2009

Stellenbosch University/Universiteit Stellenbosch

Abroad studies, International Business, 2006 - 2007

Activities and Societies: International Marking International Business International Human Rescource

Igor E.

Singapore

Audit Manager-Financial Service/Asset Management



Profile Notes and Activity (3)

4/3/2017—View by Ayyaz Ahmad

4/3/2017—InMail sent by Ayyaz Ahmad ({1})

4/3/2017—Status set to "@@system.status.replied" for "AVP SVP - PE Fund" by